<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Unscripted (Posts about beta)</title><link>https://unscriptedvn.dev/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://unscriptedvn.dev/categories/beta.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:software@marquiskurt.net"&gt;Marquis Kurt&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 17:09:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Captain's Devlog: September-October 2020</title><link>https://unscriptedvn.dev/posts/2020/10/18/captains-devlog-september-october-2020/</link><dc:creator>Marquis Kurt</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;!--
# Captain's Devlog: September-October 2020

#writing #devlog #unscripted
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time sure flies when you're having fun... or stuck in the middle of a pandemic. With that said, it's time for me to make an update on what's been happening with Unscripted in the past few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fixing bugs (of bugs, of bugs, of bugs)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides minor quality-of-life improvements, the past developer beta cycles have focused on doing lots of bug fixes. While Unscripted does include lots of interesting things, it suffers from bug creep, and the next few betas to insiders have tried to squash a lot of them. The latest betas have been focusing on the minigame's bugs, and I'm pleased to say that the minigame is a lot more polished now than in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Testing, One-Two&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in May, I launched the Unscripted Playtesting Program as a means of getting feedback for Unscripted. Since then, I've received lots of reports that have helped make the game better now than when I launched the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had launched the Steam page for Unscripted, which was something I was hesitant about at first. Thanks to feedback and internal discussion, I pushed through. After publishing the page, I started testing Unscripted through Steam to see if there were any hiccups. I'm pleased to say that, as of right now, no reports have arose due to an issue with Steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steam aside, I recently moved the playtesting program to its own separate page, &lt;a href="https://beta.unscriptedvn.dev"&gt;https://beta.unscriptedvn.dev&lt;/a&gt;. This portal aims to help centralize a lot of developer-related things such as beta release notes, reports, and update announcements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end of 2020 is coming a lot closer than anyone's probably anticipated. With this in mind, I feel confident that the major features of Unscripted have been solidified. I hope to accomplish the following things before working on finalizing the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, a slight update to the minigame where players can use pre-made NadiaVM scripts in the interactive mode to speed up the game a bit. I'm undecided on how this will work, but I'm confident I'll think of something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, focus on completing the story. Most of the chapters have been written, but I'd like to get the last couple of chapters done to wrap up the game and tell the story I want to tell. Now that features should be done, I can spend the rest of the time to finalize the story.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Furthermore, I aim to fix any continuity issues, bland parts, and in-cohesive parts of the story so that it flows better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If time allows, I'll try to add more choices to get specific dialogue points, though it isn't guaranteed at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, I will focus on gathering the rest of the assets needed for the game, including CGs and music. The story and game itself is fine at the moment, but it doesn't feel unique or as polished yet. I think adding new music and CG assets can greatly improve in this department.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, I will do my best to squash any remaining bugs. I'd like to get Unscripted to be as bug-free as it can be while still maintaining the "developer" image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot going on for the remainder of Unscripted's development, and I can't wait to share a final product with you all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/unscripted-2?utm_source=badge-featured&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_souce=badge-unscripted-2" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="https://api.producthunt.com/widgets/embed-image/v1/featured.svg?post_id=270928&amp;amp;theme=light" alt="Unscripted - A visual novel about software development | Product Hunt" style="width: 250px; height: 54px;" width="250" height="54"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>beta</category><category>devlog</category><category>steam</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://unscriptedvn.dev/posts/2020/10/18/captains-devlog-september-october-2020/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 02:10:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Captain's Devlog: July-August 2020</title><link>https://unscriptedvn.dev/posts/2020/08/22/captains-devlog-july-august-2020/</link><dc:creator>Marquis Kurt</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey, folks! It's about that time again where I give some insight on what's been going on with Unscripted. Get comfortable; I got a lot to tell you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A brand new identity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://img.itch.zone/aW1nLzM5NTcwMDcucG5n/original/zkmTli.png" alt="Itch.io header"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in May/June, I started working on bringing a new, adaptable look to Unscripted, built off of the Ayu color scheme. This feature is ready to go in the game and the look has also been adopted on the official website. The Itch.io page also saw an interface update to better match the colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late June, Apple unveiled a new look for macOS Big Sur during their WWDC event. I wanted to make Unscripted feel at home on the new update while giving it the signature identity it's had since inception. So, with the new macOS Big Sur icons, I've given the Unscripted brand more subtlety. Gone are the random bubble artworks from before; in their place, we're using gradients with Unscripted's signature brand colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A better minigame has landed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://unscriptedvn.dev/assets/img/preview3.png" alt="New minigame look"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since June, I've been working on giving the minigame in Unscripted a major overhaul. As it exists in the demo, it felt more of a tacked-on gimmick with no potential meaning whatsoever. In my previous devlog, I stated that I wanted to change that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that, within the next month or so, I will have a fully working rewrite of the minigame with more appealing visuals, a coherent plot, and a new input mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, I've made several improvements to the minigame:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, the visuals. Gone is the tacky minigame look with some mastodon and coins. Now, the tileset consists of pixel art walls, floors, desks, etc. The main character is no longer a mastodon but Mia, an employee at a tech startup company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, there are several improvements to the Fira API and NadiaVM language. New features like interactive modes, comment support, and a more direct way of controlling the player via the API exist in the library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, there's a brand-new basic mode that utilizes the interactive mode in NadiaVM to send commands and play levels in real time, without complilation. I think this is a more fun way of playing the minigame than attempting to push buttons and guess the correct order to push them in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Besides the API and interactive improvements, the minigame now includes little "glitches" that also act as game mechanics. These bugs are to be exploited by the player to solve the puzzle, giving the game an interesting approach to solving puzzles. Sadly, we couldn't fit any portals in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, the minigame will be better integrated into the game's plot by becoming the game that you, the player, are publishing to the PackStore Arcade! Parts of the story have been rewritten to accomodate for this change, and I hope to add more levels and content to the minigame that make it feel integrated, yet stand out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm super excited for this updated minigame. It's arguably a lot more fun to play around with (and more fun to work on), and I can't wait for you all to get your hands on it when the final game releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The core is open (and other cool developer stuff)!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may recall in my previous devlog about my plans to take some parts of Unscripted and make then open source:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to make Unscripted a place to go to learn new things and try out what's available with Python and Ren'Py just like how I did when making mods for DDLC, so I've decided that I will be open-sourcing some core utilities and modules inside of the game itself known as the Unscripted Core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some more playtesting builds, I've made the source code publicly available. Although the code is still a work in progress, it's available for tinkering on GitHub under the Mozilla Public License, v2.0 at &lt;a href="https://github.com/UnscriptedVN/core"&gt;https://github.com/UnscriptedVN/core&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other open-source news, I recently created a new Python library for Unscripted's changelog format. This library is used in-game to read the changelog and display the latest features when you launch the game after an update. Known as Simple Changes (&lt;code&gt;simplechanges&lt;/code&gt;), this library is available in PyPI and the source code is also available on GitHub. Additionally, I recently published a Visual Studio Code extension, the &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=marquiskurt.uvn-lang-pack"&gt;Unscripted Language Pack&lt;/a&gt;, that adds NadiaVM and SimpleChanges (.changes) as languages and provides basic syntax highlighting. If you're using Simple Changes and/or want to edit the minigame's NadiaVM files in style, this is the extension for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://unscriptedvn.dev/assets/img/posts/docs-center.png" alt="Documentation Center Homepage"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I'm pleased to say that there's a unified place for the documentation of all Unscripted open-source projects: the documentation center! The Documentation Center is available at &lt;a href="https://docs.unscriptedvn.dev"&gt;https://docs.unscriptedvn.dev&lt;/a&gt; and covers all of the docs for Fira, Unscripted Core, Simple Changes, and the Ren'Py Distribution Tools I launched back in December. This should make searching for documentation much easier and a pleasure to use. I highly recommend checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Oh, the places we can go!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the inception of this project, Unscripted has been available on Itch.io in demo form. Itch.io has been a wonderful place and storefront to host Unscripted on. Many people have downloaded and seen Unscripted from this place, and adding updates has been a smooth process. Recently, I took a look at a bunch of feedback from the playesting program and, after some careful consideration, launched the official Steam page for Unscripted! I worked with an amazing team to help assemble the trailer together, and I spent a good amount of time learning how to upload builds to Steam. After waiting for a review from Valve, the page finally launched in mid-August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the page and add Unscripted to your wishlist here: &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1379980/Unscripted/"&gt;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1379980/Unscripted/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm super excited to bring Unscripted to Steam, and I hope you are as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This just about covers the major points for the past two months. I can't wait to share what's in store soon!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>beta</category><category>devlog</category><category>steam</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://unscriptedvn.dev/posts/2020/08/22/captains-devlog-july-august-2020/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 18:29:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Captain's Devlog: May-June 2020</title><link>https://unscriptedvn.dev/posts/2020/06/15/captains-devlog-may-june-2020/</link><dc:creator>Marquis Kurt</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been about a couple of months since I wrote the last devlog that outline what's been going on, and I figured it's time for me to do the same thing again since I haven't posted much on the official site. Here's a rundown of what's been happing the past few weeks with Unscripted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Extended demo updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I published the v1.2.4 release of the extended demo, which contained a couple of bugfixes and improvements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolves an issue where the AliceOS desktop could be called infinitely on the call stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds argument options via arguments.toml.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds a glossary page in Help with terms and definitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds use cases for inventory items in some parts of the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes notification toast when an item is received to the game’s default, not AliceOS’s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removes documented features in Help that don’t exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine that, unless there are major flaws in the current release of the extended demo, there won't be any future updates as development builds will most likely break compatibility with older releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hello, Ayu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past two weeks, I've been working on making Unscripted's user interface and brand consistent. Part of this included reconsidering the color scheme and general user interface look. After some deliberation, I've worked on implementing a variation of the popular &lt;a href="https://github.com/ayu-theme/ayu-colors"&gt;Ayu color scheme&lt;/a&gt; as the theme for Unscripted. Ayu offers vibrant colors and a great set of colors to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://unscriptedvn.dev/assets/img/posts/ayu-scrn.png" class="ms-shadowed"&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-top:2px"&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;In-game screenshot of Ayu Light theme.&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://unscriptedvn.dev/assets/img/posts/ayu-prefs.png" class="ms-shadowed"&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-top:2px"&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;Appearance page in Ayu Dark theme.&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Ayu offers light, blue, and dark variations of the color scheme, I've implemented a new theme system for the game and include all three variations. The official website also got a bit of a makeover to include the new colors, as well as the Itch.io page. I've also implemented some quality-of-life additions to the game to customize its appearance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now select which font you want to use for dialogue as well as its size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Merriweather and OpenDyslexic fonts have been added as font options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lexend fonts are now a sub-page to Appearance (&lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt; › &lt;strong&gt;Appearance&lt;/strong&gt; › &lt;strong&gt;Dialogue font&lt;/strong&gt; › &lt;strong&gt;Lexend...&lt;/strong&gt;) instead of a slider. This should hopefully resolve some font selection issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Calling all playtesters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://unscriptedvn.dev/assets/img/playtest.png" alt="Playtesting Program promo image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the past months, I've also been on the hunt for playtesters to get feedback of the game as it's being developed. I've consulted people on Twitter, Reddit, and Discord as I continue to work on the game. I've gotten feedback from a few people and have made improvements to the game as I receive more suggestions. Previously, I had been only accepting members on a limited basis since I was still working out the kinks in the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that everything's all organized and ready to go, I've decided to open the game up to more playtesters on a semi-public beta program known as the &lt;strong&gt;Unscripted Playtesting Program&lt;/strong&gt;. The playtesting program is a great way to get involved and give feedback on the project as I develop it. The new &lt;a href="https://unscriptedvn.dev/pages/playtests/"&gt;playtesting program page&lt;/a&gt; outlines the process, requirements, and what happens in the beta program. I welcome and encourage players to try out the latest development builds and help make Unscripted reach its full potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unscripted ♥️ open-source and GitHub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in late 2019/early 2020, I released the &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/renpy-distribute-tools"&gt;Ren'Py Distribution Tools&lt;/a&gt; module (&lt;code&gt;renpy-distribute-tools&lt;/code&gt;) as an open-source module on GitHub to help streamline distribution of visual novel projects. This module has made its way to PyPI and migrated over to a new place on GitHub for all Unscripted-related code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://unscriptedvn.dev/assets/img/posts/gh.png" alt="GitHub organization page"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, there have been a couple of other repositories open:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/UnscriptedVN/mastina"&gt;&lt;code&gt;mastina&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a Nikola theme for the Unscripted website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/UnscriptedVN/fira"&gt;&lt;code&gt;fira&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the backend and API mechanisms for the current minigame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might also recall in an earlier post that a &lt;a href="https://github.com/UnscriptedVN/issues"&gt;new GitHub repository is available&lt;/a&gt; to report bugs and request features for the game, which replaced YouTrack. GitHub is also where a lot of work on Unscripted takes place, ranging from the minigame to the core story. With the new playtesting program in place, this also is where a lot of developer builds for testing take place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, open-source software is what makes Unscripted possible; libraries such as &lt;code&gt;discord-rpc&lt;/code&gt; and projects like Ren'Py, Inter, and Feather icons have helped bring Unscripted together to the game it is today. I make it a point to thank the open-source community by acknowledging them in both the credits and the game's license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why bring up open-source software and GitHub? I personally am a believer in open-source software; open-source software has helped me grow as a developer and has taught me a lot of valuable things. Open-source modding projects for DDLC have also taught me a lot of what I know with both Python and Ren'Py.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I anticipate that some players and developers may want to better understand how I do some things in Unscripted or may want to contribute to the project to catch any bugs. I want to make Unscripted a place to go to learn new things and try out what's available with Python and Ren'Py just like how I did when making mods for DDLC, so I've decided that I will be open-sourcing some core utilities and modules inside of the game itself known as the Unscripted Core. In fact, I made this decision all the way back in &lt;em&gt;January&lt;/em&gt;; some of the demo builds use this new open-source code!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is mostly set up to handle open-sourcing Unscripted Core. In the final release of the game, the source code for Unscripted Core will be available right in the game as a standard Ren'Py archive. You can also expect to see the GitHub repository available in the following weeks, licensed under the Mozilla Public License v2.0, the same license used in Unscripted Fira, Mastina, and the Ren'Py Distribution Tools. I can't wait to reveal what's been under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;An overhaul of the minigame... again...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://unscriptedvn.dev/assets/img/posts/mg.png" alt="Minigame"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I released the extended demo, I introduced a brand new minigame where players control a mastodon with a series of commands, either by clicking buttons or using Python, to collect a bunch of coins and reach the end of the map. After receiving some feedback from playtesters, I realize that the minigame isn't the most enjoyable thing in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that, within the next month or so, I will have a fully working rewrite of the minigame with more appealing visuals, a coherent plot, and a new input mechanic. In the coming weeks, I also intend to rework the story a bit to turn the minigame into the game that the main character will eventually publish to the PackStore. I will post details on the progress I've made on the minigame as they get developed; I've got some exciting ideas that will be interesting to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this was a long devlog, but I thank you for reading all the way through. I look forward to sharing more information on Unscripted's progress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Marquis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>beta</category><category>devlog</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://unscriptedvn.dev/posts/2020/06/15/captains-devlog-may-june-2020/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 13:02:03 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>