<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Unscripted (Posts about demo)</title><link>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/categories/demo.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:unscriptedvn@marquiskurt.net"&gt;Marquis Kurt&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 17:49:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Releasing a hotfix for v1.1.0-demo1</title><link>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2020/01/31/releasing-a-hotfix-for-v110-demo1/</link><dc:creator>Marquis Kurt</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Howdy, folks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm releasing a quick (but important) hotfix of the feature update for the Unscripted Demo feature update (v1.1.0-demo1). There's not much to this update, but it should resolve the missing start label issue found on Windows (see &lt;a href="https://youtrack.marquiskurt.net/youtrack/issue/UVN-43"&gt;UVN-43&lt;/a&gt;). Additionally, it brings a new version of the demo license that better explains the terms and conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feature and improvement-wise, there aren't a lot of changes to the game in this update that affect the gameplay. However, this is the first version of Unscripted Demo that uses the new build system that the current developer project uses, so the Ren'Py archives are slightly different and some things might function a little bit differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your continued patience, and I can't wait to get the full game out later this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Marquis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bugfix</category><category>demo</category><category>update</category><guid>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2020/01/31/releasing-a-hotfix-for-v110-demo1/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 21:24:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>First feature update for Unscripted Demo</title><link>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2020/01/27/first-feature-update-for-unscripted-demo/</link><dc:creator>Marquis Kurt</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Howdy, everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've released a new feature update for the Unscripted demo (v1.1.0-demo1) that brings some new improvements. Here's what's in the update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambient sounds&lt;/strong&gt;: Unscripted now has ambient sounds! You can adjust the ambient volume in Settings and listen to appropriate background sounds while playing. This will also automatically adjust with "Emphasize sound effects" turned on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christina updates&lt;/strong&gt;: Christina's eye color has been updated to a hazel color instead of just brown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QuickMail&lt;/strong&gt;: The first email you receive has been re-written to better reflect Christina's personality. She's not the pushy type...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desktop image&lt;/strong&gt;: The desktop image has been updated to wave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save/load slots&lt;/strong&gt;: The UI for save and load slots has been improved and now has a respective delete button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those wondering about the inventory state issue, that has been patched into the full game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing Unscripted, and I hope you enjoy these new improvements!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Marquis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>demo</category><category>feature</category><category>update</category><guid>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2020/01/27/first-feature-update-for-unscripted-demo/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 21:42:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Second bugfix for Unscripted demo</title><link>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2019/12/26/second-bugfix-for-unscripted-demo/</link><dc:creator>Marquis Kurt</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Howdy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've released another bug fix release of the demo to Unscripted today. This mostly is a continuation of fixing issues with inventory item duplications (&lt;a href="https://youtrack.marquiskurt.net/youtrack/issue/UVN-33"&gt;UVN-33&lt;/a&gt;). The following should now be fixed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When starting a new game after saving a game, the inventory should now clear itself in the beginning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rolling back and forth in a particular save will no longer re-run the item addition, causing duplicates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Inventory HUD is a lot cleaner now and doesn't open if you aren't carrying anything. (You can also toggle the E key to open and close it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this fixes all of the issues with the way inventories are implemented, but I'm on the lookout for anything else that crops up. As always, if you do find something fishy with the demo release, report it on YouTrack! You can do so from the main menu with the "Report a Bug" option or head to the website yourself: &lt;a href="https://1n.pm/AsuXE"&gt;https://1n.pm/AsuXE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, and I hope you all keep enjoying Unscripted!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bugfix</category><category>demo</category><guid>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2019/12/26/second-bugfix-for-unscripted-demo/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 18:24:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A quick hot fix update for the demo</title><link>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2019/12/24/a-quick-hot-fix-update-for-the-demo/</link><dc:creator>Marquis Kurt</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Howdy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all of those who got their hands on the demo! I've just released a quick patch update that fixes a couple of issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emails should now work properly in-game (fixes &lt;a href="https://youtrack.marquiskurt.net/youtrack/issue/UVN-32"&gt;UVN-32&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB drives should now not take over your inventory and multiply when you roll back (fixes &lt;a href="https://youtrack.marquiskurt.net/youtrack/issue/UVN-33"&gt;UVN-33&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find any more issues, please do let me know on YouTrack! Thanks again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bugfix</category><category>demo</category><guid>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2019/12/24/a-quick-hot-fix-update-for-the-demo/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 18:24:05 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>