<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Unscripted (Posts about devlog)</title><link>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/categories/devlog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:unscriptedvn@marquiskurt.net"&gt;Marquis Kurt&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 14:39:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>v1.2.3 has been released, and a new issue tracker!</title><link>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2020/05/15/v123-has-been-released-and-a-new-issue-tracker/</link><dc:creator>Marquis Kurt</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey, everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've pushed out an update with tons of quality of life improvements and bug fixes. If you find anything out of the ordinary or encounter a new bug, let me know! You can join the Discord server and tell me there, or use the issue tracker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the issue tracker, there's been a big change regarding bug reports. Since I started coding Unscripted, I used the YouTrack issue tracker to manage issues related to the game, and it's served me well thus far. However, there are some limitations with YouTrack currently, and it's not the best experience for play testers or regular players; it's still heavily developer-oriented and may be daunting. After working with my team and a handful of play testers, I'm pleased to announce that we're going all in with GitHub!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with this release, if you want to file a bug report or make a feature request, create an issue on GitHub at &lt;a href="https://github.com/UnscriptedVN/issues/issues/"&gt;https://github.com/UnscriptedVN/issues/issues/&lt;/a&gt;. You can also click the message icon in the game menu or press Shift+B while in-game to open GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the full changelog for those who are interested:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolves an issue where minigame levels with "collect" in Basic Mode fail due to incorrect VM code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes a couple of minor typos, including pronoun conjugation agreement issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolves an issue where attempting to view the license on a read-only file system fails (IOError).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds more details about the different game modes and a preview image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds new "Warp Speed" option to minigame preview animation speeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds options to show hidden NadiaVM commands and reduce spacing in VM preview window in Basic Mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds an option to forcefully show the editor in Advanced Mode when an existing VM file is present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves minigame experience by rolling back to last checkpoint if an error occurs during the minigame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevents minigame overriding between modes by namespacing NadiaVM based on game mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds keybinding 'l' to open the Unscripted log file (or select it in the file browser).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makes AliceOS Desktop keybind ('d') universally available, not just the game menu or in the quick menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates Fira API, which includes fixes for reporting proper list coordinates when calling "as_list".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increases the font contrast on muted text colors in the game menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds message bubble around NVL text in chat history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renames "John Doe" on empty saves to "Foo Bar" to be gender neutral.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removes "entitlements.plist" from Windows and Linux builds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds option to display the chapter number and chapter title when switching to a new chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes some hiding animations of characters to the side instead of the standard hide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes default tab in Help to About instead of Keyboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes RepoHive icon to a flat icon to remain visually consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved new credits screen with condensed spacing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds keybinding 'Shift+B' to open the bug reporter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaces "Back", "Hub", "Report a Bug", and "Quit" with icon buttons in game menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moves back button in the game menu to far left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moves bug reporter button in the game menu to far right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes alignment of the game menu buttons on the right side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates bug reporting links to new issue tracking pages on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy this update as much as I did writing it, and I look forward to any bug reports or feature requests on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Marquis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>devlog</category><category>github</category><category>update</category><guid>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2020/05/15/v123-has-been-released-and-a-new-issue-tracker/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 18:07:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Captain's Devlog: March-April 2020</title><link>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2020/04/02/devlog-march-april-2020/</link><dc:creator>Marquis Kurt</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since my last update to the demo was released (about a month or two, I believe), and I haven't released much since then. However, there are a couple of things I'd like to tell you all about what's been going on with Unscripted the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A new character steps forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After publishing the demo, I went to work into writing more of the full story with multiple routes. Unfortunately, I was kind of a bit struck with writer's block and needed to find a solution before starting to lose interest. Luckily, I figured out a solution that I think this visual novel deserves: a new, fourth character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/assets/img/posts/fira1.png" alt="Meredith 1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of a week ago, I teamed up with Raseruuu, the game's sprite artist, to bring her to life into the game. This new character, "Meredith" (legal name), is the first non-programmer in the game and has a unique personality that I think you'll all love learning more about as much I have been writing for her!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It's Rush Drawing time!!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;new sprite for Unscripted VN&lt;br&gt;I need that commission money uguu, salary hasn't come uwaaa&lt;a href="https://t.co/eMFqIvvuxC"&gt;https://t.co/eMFqIvvuxC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/b465RRWMtZ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/b465RRWMtZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Zan Kizuna @SoftWar (@Raseruuuuu) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Raseruuuuu/status/1242428269963567111?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 24, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expanding the minigame&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that I wanted to add more to the minigame that Unscripted offers. For those that may not be familiar, Unscripted includes a minigame in which you control Mastina, a mastodon, through a world, collecting coins in the process. The minigame currently uses a set of buttons that a player clicks in a specific order to solve the puzzle, but I know that I personally would prefer to have the flexibility of writing a script rather than entering one in manually with a user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/assets/img/posts/api.png" alt="API"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the Unscripted Minigame API. The Minigame API is part of a bigger chunk of the minigame's advanced mode where players can write Python scripts to solve the puzzle instead of using the buttons. This should give experienced (and new) players/developers the flexibility that Python offers while allowing players to write sensible code and interact with the minigame that wouldn't be possible otherwise. I've also been working on writing some solid documentation that explains the API in great detail and everything you need to know to write great scripts to solve puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;So... extended demo?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's been a really &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZRpoA1PLKF?amp=1"&gt;fun playthrough of Unscripted's demo that I've watched&lt;/a&gt;, and the YouTuber, Cryptic Hybrid, brought up the question of possibly releasing an extended demo. After some thinking and working on the new character and advanced mode of the minigame, I will probably release an extended demo. The demo will come as a traditional feature update to the game, and it will probably include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More chapters available to where all characters have been introduced. This will let players meet each character, especially the new addition to the team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some minigame puzzles, with the advanced mode ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New iconography for the app on Windows and macOS that best represent the platforms they're running on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new start screen for a new game that lets you choose your programming language and pronoun preferences in addition to your name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Possibly) Some scenes with CGs. Because they're always fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to keep up with the dev-logging and let you know more about Unscripted as I keep developing it. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Marquis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>devlog</category><guid>https://unscripted.marquiskurt.net/posts/2020/04/02/devlog-march-april-2020/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 01:15:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>